<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>World - Los Angeles Times</title>
    <link>http://www.latimes.com/world/rss2.0.xml</link>
    <description>Coverage of the top world news stories from across the globe, including politics, breaking news and opinion.</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>&#xA9;2017 Los Angeles Times</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 05:49:25 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
    <title>Watch dramatic video showing North Korean forces chasing, firing on defecting soldier</title>
	<dc:creator>Matt Stiles</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-north-korea-defector-20171121-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>United States military officials Wednesday released dramatic video showing the daring defection — and eventual rescue — of a North Korean soldier who barreled across the Demilitarized Zone in a truck and then ran as fellow troops fired on him.</p> <p>The video, shot the afternoon of Nov. 13, shows the...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 20:30:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a15204c/turbine/la-fg-north-korea-defector-20171121/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Russia&apos;s military role in Syria may be nearing an end, Putin says after meeting with Assad</title>
	<dc:creator>Sabra Ayres, Alexandra Zavis, Tracy Wilkinson</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-assad-putin-meet-20171120-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>To many observers, the image of Russian President Vladimir Putin sharing a warm embrace with Syrian leader Bashar Assad during a surprise meeting between the two leaders seemed to serve as a coda to a Russian military campaign that has reversed the course of a ferocious war now in its seventh year.</p>...
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 19:55:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a14ff8d/turbine/la-fg-assad-putin-meet-20171120/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Zimbabwe&apos;s Robert Mugabe, facing impeachment, resigns after 37 years in power</title>
	<dc:creator>Robyn Dixon, Godwin Mangudya</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-zimbabwe-impeachment-20171121-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>Robert Mugabe, the revolutionary war hero who helped end white minority rule in Zimbabwe but replaced it with decades of brutality and corruption, had always said he would give up power on his own terms and rule until he was 100.</p> <p>In the end, he did neither: The 93-year-old president, facing impeachment,...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 17:05:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a14d722/turbine/la-fg-zimbabwe-impeachment-20171121/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>The rise and fall of Zimbabwe&apos;s longtime leader: Robert Mugabe</title>
	<dc:creator>Ann M. Simmons</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-robert-mugabe-timeline-20171121-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>The rule of Robert Mugabe, a once-respected liberation leader turned feared dictator and international pariah, came to an unflattering end Tuesday when the Zimbabwean president was forced to relinquish his 37-year hold on power in the face of possible impeachment.</p> <p>The future of the 93-year-old...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 16:05:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a14d24b/turbine/la-fg-robert-mugabe-timeline-20171121/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Two high-profile killings in Mexico stoke outrage about nationwide surge in slayings</title>
	<dc:creator>Patrick J. McDonnell</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-mexico-killings-20171121-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>Public indignation about Mexico’s surging homicide rate has followed the two latest high-profile killings — those of a human rights ombudsman in Baja California Sur state and a telecommunications executive outside Mexico City.</p> <p>President Enrique Peña Nieto denounced the killing of Adolfo Lagos Espinosa,...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 15:20:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a14c0c8/turbine/la-fg-mexico-killings-20171121/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>A mother waits at the edge of the ocean for a son whose submarine has gone missing</title>
	<dc:creator>Andres D&amp;apos;Alessandro, Chris Kraul</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-argentina-submarine-families-20171121-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>Family members of 44 crew members of the Argentine submarine missing for nearly a week have maintained brave faces even as each passing hour complicates chances for a rescue of their loved ones lost at sea.</p> <p>“Every so often I go to the edge of the ocean and ask that my son be returned to me,” said...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 14:15:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a14d659/turbine/la-fg-argentina-submarine-families-20171121/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Sounds heard in deep ocean were not distress signals from missing submarine, Argentine navy says</title>
	<dc:creator>Andres D&amp;apos;Alessandro and Chris Kraul</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-argentina-submarine-search-20172021-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p></p><p>Hopes that strange sounds detected on the ocean floor might be distress signals from a missing Argentine submarine crew were dashed Monday night after an analysis indicated they were not metallic in nature.</p> <p></p><p>Earlier in the day, Argentine navy spokesman Enrique Balbi said the noises picked up by...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 18:20:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a138f0f/turbine/la-fg-argentina-submarine-search-20172021/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Trump puts North Korea back on list of &apos;state sponsors of terrorism&apos;</title>
	<dc:creator>Tracy Wilkinson, Noah Bierman</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-na-pol-trump-north-korea-20171120-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>President Trump put North Korea back on a U.S. list of “state sponsors of terrorism” Monday, a largely symbolic move that administration officials said will increase pressure on Pyongyang to give up its nuclear weapons arsenal.</p> <p>Trump said the designation will be followed Tuesday by a new round...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 14:50:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a136abd/turbine/la-na-pol-trump-north-korea-20171120/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Germany faces uncertain political future as talks on new coalition government collapse</title>
	<dc:creator>Erik Kirschbaum</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-germany-talks-20171120-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>German Chancellor Angela Merkel said Monday that she would rather face another election than try to muddle through with a minority government if further negotiations did not yield coalition partners.</p> <p>Merkel’s comments came after talks to form a new government unexpectedly collapsed late Sunday,...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 14:25:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a1359f0/turbine/la-fg-germany-talks-20171120/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Trump urged to sell $50 million in lethal weapons to Ukraine</title>
	<dc:creator>Tracy Wilkinson</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-na-pol-ukraine-weapons-20171120-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>National security officials are urging President Trump to approve the sale of nearly $50 million worth of U.S. weapons to Ukraine, which has confronted what it sees as military aggression from Russia and pro-Russian separatists for years.</p> <p>It was unclear whether Trump, who has been reluctant to...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 13:20:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a134e22/turbine/la-na-pol-ukraine-weapons-20171120/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Zimbabwe&apos;s Mugabe may face impeachment after failing to meet resignation deadline</title>
	<dc:creator>Robyn Dixon</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-zimbabwe-deadline-resign-20171120-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>Zimbabwe’s ruling party expects to start impeachment proceedings against longtime President Robert Mugabe in parliament Tuesday, after he failed to meet a deadline set by the party for him to step down.</p> <p>Mugabe has clung to the presidency amid increasing pressure from party leaders, much of the...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 13:00:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a136f28/turbine/la-fg-zimbabwe-deadline-resign-20171120/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Chile&apos;s presidential race appears headed for a December runoff</title>
	<dc:creator>Jorge Poblete, Chris Kraul</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-chile-elections-20171119-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>Businessman Sebastian Piñera, who was Chile’s president from 2010 to 2014, appeared headed for a victory in presidential elections Sunday, though a runoff was expected with the second-place finisher, according to partial returns.</p> <p>Piñera and the other candidates seemed likely to fall short of the...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 18:55:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a12448f/turbine/la-fg-chile-elections-20171119/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Zimbabwe&apos;s Mugabe remains president, at least temporarily, after ruling party fires him</title>
	<dc:creator>Robyn Dixon</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-zimbabwe-mugabe-20171119-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>Zimbabwean President Robert Mugabe, who was widely expected to resign Sunday after the ruling party sacked him and threatened to impeach him if he did not leave office, conceded a need for change but remained in the leadership post.</p> <p>Mugabe, stripped of executive power when the military took control...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 16:05:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a12407d/turbine/la-fg-zimbabwe-mugabe-20171119/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Argentine officials cannot confirm whether satellite signals came from missing submarine</title>
	<dc:creator>Andres D&amp;apos;Alessandro, Chris Kraul</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-argentina-submarine-search-20171119-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>Argentina’s navy said Sunday that there was no clear evidence that satellite communications initially believed to have come from a submarine with 44 crew members missing in the Atlantic were from the vessel.</p> <p>Officials said they were analyzing whether seven brief satellite calls the Defense Ministry...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 15:35:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a130a01/turbine/la-fg-argentina-submarine-search-20171119/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>The Shakespearean excesses and political intrigues that drove Africa&apos;s oldest strongman out of power</title>
	<dc:creator>Robyn Dixon</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-zimbabwe-mugabe-last-days-20171119-htmlstory.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  Robert Mugabe, remote, aloof and arrogant, regards himself as the last of the African liberation war heroes, with no living peers left. He carefully created the militaristic state that kept him in power for 37 years, forgetting that once he lost control of the generals, he was finished.
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 06:00:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a10fe9d/turbine/la-fg-zimbabwe-mugabe-last-days-20171119/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Missing Argentine submarine apparently sent 7 satellite messages, but none got through</title>
	<dc:creator>Andres D&amp;apos;Alessandro, Chris Kraul</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-argentina-submarine-20171118-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>The Argentine navy has detected what appeared to be seven satellite messages sent from a missing submarine, but communication with the vessel was never established, and its whereabouts in the south Atlantic remained a mystery late Saturday.</p> <p>The 44-crew submarine, the subject of an intensive search...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 20:25:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a1308e0/turbine/la-fg-argentina-submarine-20171118/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Lebanon&apos;s prime minister arrives in Paris, heralding the end of one crisis but perhaps starting another</title>
	<dc:creator>Nabih Bulos</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-hariri-paris-20171118-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>Lebanon’s embattled prime minister, Saad Hariri, met with French President Emmanuel Macron in Paris on Saturday and insisted he would return to Beirut on Wednesday, marking a new chapter in the odd political drama that has thrust Lebanon into the regional rivalry between Saudi Arabia and Iran.</p> ...
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 14:50:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a10cca9/turbine/la-fg-hariri-paris-20171118/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Trump administration threatens to shut down Palestinian delegation in Washington</title>
	<dc:creator>Noga Tarnopolsky</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-plo-israel-20171118-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>The Trump administration is threatening to shutter the Palestinian Authority’s representative office in Washington based on a provision of a U.S. law that has not been previously enforced.</p> <p>The State Department recently informed the Palestinian Authority that if it does not reenter peace negotiations...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 13:40:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a14fc52/turbine/la-fg-plo-israel-20171118/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Trump administration updates demands as NAFTA talks continue</title>
	<dc:creator>Don Lee</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fi-nafta-updated-objectives-20171118-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>President Trump’s top trade official has issued new objectives for renegotiating the North American Free Trade Agreement — including some likely to irk Canada and Mexico, as well as the U.S. recording industry and other major business interests, as talks continue this weekend.</p> <p>There are few surprises...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 13:15:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a10c188/turbine/la-fi-nafta-updated-objectives-20171118/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Thousands march through Zimbabwe&apos;s capital to demand Mugabe&apos;s departure</title>
	<dc:creator>Robyn Dixon</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-zimbabwe-mugabe-protest-20171118-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>During elections nine years ago, Zimbabwe ruling party thugs banged on Nonoza Ncube’s door at 2 a.m., took her to a temporary military-style base and beat her on her back and legs with batons.</p> <p>Yet when she heard that ruling party ZANU-PF war veterans were staging a mass rally in Harare, the nation’s...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 12:00:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a10d26e/turbine/la-fg-zimbabwe-mugabe-protest-20171118/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>After backlash, Trump says he will postpone plan to allow elephant trophy imports</title>
	<dc:creator>Matt Pearce</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-na-trump-elephants-20171117-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>In a surprise move, the Trump administration will suspend its recent decision to allow hunters to bring elephant trophies back to the U.S. from parts of southern Africa, President Trump announced Friday night on Twitter.</p> <p>The move comes as celebrities, politicians and even some Trump supporters...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 18:25:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a10c2cc/turbine/la-na-trump-elephants-20171117/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>As Trump administration touts coal at U.N. gathering, U.S. cities and states target climate change</title>
	<dc:creator>Erik Kirschbaum</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-germany-climate-change-20171117-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>The sharp political divisions in the United States over climate change spilled over to the outside world at the United Nations conference that will likely be remembered for two rival delegations that showed up from the U.S.</p> <p>As Trump administration officials attending a U.N. climate change conference...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 17:10:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a0f88f0/turbine/la-fg-germany-climate-change-20171117/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Congressional critics slam State Department as rudderless</title>
	<dc:creator>Tracy Wilkinson</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-na-pol-state-department-20171117-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>When Secretary of State Rex Tillerson made his first official trip to Myanmar on Wednesday, he did not describe the country’s brutal military crackdown on Rohingya Muslims as ethnic cleansing, as other diplomats have done.</p> <p>Security forces have conducted or allowed what critics call systematic rape...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 15:00:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a10d543/turbine/la-na-pol-state-department-20171117/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Zimbabwe President Robert Mugabe makes first public appearance since military takeover</title>
	<dc:creator>Robyn Dixon</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-mugabe-zimbabwe-20171117-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>Zimbabwean President Robert Mugabe’s public appearance at a university graduation ceremony Friday — leaving the confinement of his mansion — was stage-managed by the military to deflect accusations it took control of the country Wednesday in a military coup.</p> <p>The move was designed to assure neighboring...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 13:50:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a0f5b85/turbine/la-fg-mugabe-zimbabwe-20171117/600"/>
      </item>
<item>
    <title>Latest round of NAFTA talks opens in Mexico, with few prospects for breakthroughs</title>
	<dc:creator>Patrick J. McDonnell, Cecilia Sanchez</dc:creator>
	<link>http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-mexico-nafta-20171117-story.html</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p>Mexico is signaling both flexibility and doubt about the latest demands from Washington as the fifth round of talks on the future of the North American Free Trade Agreement formally opened Friday in the Mexican capital.</p> <p>The fate of NAFTA has become a kind of national fixation in Mexico, where the...</p>
	]]></description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 12:35:00 PST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail url="http://www.trbimg.com/img-5a0f483b/turbine/la-fg-mexico-nafta-20171117/600"/>
      </item>
</channel> 
</rss>
